A Guide to the Louis Arthur Johnson Papers, ca. 1930-1964
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series II: Papers of the Assistant Secretary of War, 1936 (1937-1940)1941
  - Subseries B, Case Files, 1937-1940
    - National Defense Power Committee for Study of Electric Power Capabilities - Correspondence and Papers 1938 March-Aug. (Box 71)
    - National Defense Power Committee - Correspondence and Papers 1938 Aug.-Oct. (Box 71)
    - National Defense Power Committee - Secret and Confidential Correspondence and Papers 1938 Oct.-1939 Oct. (Box 71)
    - National Defense Power Committee - Minutes of Meetings and Papers 1939 Oct.-1940 March (Box 71)
    - National Defense Power Committee - Minutes of Meetings and Papers 1940 April-June (Box 71)
    - National Defense Program - Correspondence and Papers re: Labor and Personnel 1938 Dec. (Box 72)
    - National Defense Program - Report estimating Two-Year Program 1938 Nov.-Dec. (Box 72)
    - National Guard - Correspondence 1937 July-1940 July (Box 72)
    - National Guard of New York State - Correspondence re: Johnson's Speech at Annual Convention 1937 Dec.-1938 (Box 72)
    - National Industrial Preparedness Dinner - Correspondence re: Johnson's Address 1939 Jan.-April (Box 72)
    - National Industrial Preparedness Dinner - Correspondence 1939 April-May (Box 72)
    - National Power Policy Committee - Correspondence 1939 Oct.-1940 March (Box 72)
    - National Power Policy Committee - Summary of Conferences with Representatives of Power Systems Serving Thirteen War Materials Areas, and Report on same 1940 Jan. (Box 72)
    - National Power Policy Committee - Newspaper Clippings 1939 Oct.-1940 March (Box 72)
    - National Press Club - Correspondence re: Johnson's Membership 1937 Oct.-1939 June (Box 72)
    - Naval Ordnance Plant, Charleston, W. Va. - Correspondence and Memorandum 1937 Oct.-1938 Dec. (Box 73)
    - Navy - Related Correspondence and Papers 1938 Oct.-1940 July (Box 73)
    - Netherlands Claims Commission - Correspondence and Memoranda 1932 Dec.-1933 Aug. (Box 73)
    - Neutrality of U.S. - Correspondence with White House 1937 Sept.-Oct. (Box 73)
    - Neutrality of U.S. - Correspondence, including Papers expressing views on Neutrality 1939 Aug.-1940 Jan. (Box 73)
    - Neutrality of U.S.-Memoranda and Proceedings of Interdepartmental Committee on Neutrality 1939 Aug.-Dec. (Box 73)
    - Neutrality of U.S.-Memorandum re: Neutrality of Aircraft 1939 Aug. 24 (Box 73)
    - Neutrality of U.S.- Newspaper Clippings 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 73)
    - New York State Banker's Association - Correspondence re: Johnson's Address 1939 Dec.-1940 (Box 74)
    - The New York Times1924 Sept. 13 (Box 74)
    - Newcomb Society - Correspondence and Reports on Activities 1938-1940 (Box 74)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Miscellaneous, 2 folders 1940 Jan.-Feb. (Box 74)
    - Newspaper Clippings - Miscellaneous 1940 April (Box 74)
    - Newspaper Clippings of Articles from Press Release 1940 May (Box 74)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases - Miscellaneous 1940 June (Box 74)
    - Offers of Service to Government - Correspondence to Johnson and replies 1938 Nov.-1940 June (Box 75)
    - Offers of Service - Correspondence and Replies, 3 folders ca. 1939 Sept. - 1940 July (Box 75)
    - Official Miscellaneous - Correspondence and Memoranda, 2 folders 1937 July-1938 June (Box 75)
    - Official Miscellaneous, 3 folders 1938 June-1940 July (Box 76)
    - Orders for Establishing New Offices 1939 Aug. 29, Sept. 20 (Box 76)
    - Ordnance Procurement - Correspondence and Papers 1938 Aug. - 1940 Jan. (Box 76)
    - Panama Road - Correspondence and Papers 1938 Aug. - 1939 March (Box 76)
    - Photographs - Correspondence and Memoranda re: Photos of Johnson 1937 June - 1940 June (Box 76)
    - Presidency of Johnson - Correspondence suggesting Johnson for President 1937 Aug. - 1940 April (Box 76)
    - Press Conference of Johnson 1940 March - April (Box 76)
    - Press Releases - Miscellaneous 1940 March (Box 76)
    - Price Controls - Memorandum to General Watson from Johnson on Price Controls in War 1939 Sept. 2 (Box 76)
    - R. O. T. C. - Correspondence, 2 folders 1937 July - 1938 Nov. (Box 77)
    - Rail Transportation in War - Correspondence and Memoranda 1938 Sept.-Oct. (Box 77)
    - Reply to Hoover - Correspondence re: Johnson's Speech, 2 folders 1940 May - June (Box 77)
    - Resignation as Assistant Secretary of War - Correspondence from supporters of Johnson and replies, A-H, 2 folders 1940 July - Oct. (Box 77)
    - Resignation as Assistant Secretary of War - Correspondence from supporters of Johnson and replies, J-Z, 2 folders 1940 July-Oct. (Box 78)
    - Resignation of Secretary of War Woodring - Newspaper Clippings 1940 June (Box 78)
    - Resignation of Woodring - Newspaper Clippings 1940 June (Box 79)
    - "Rounding Out of Army" - Correspondence re: Johnson's Address 1940 July (Box 79)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. - Speeches 1939 Jan. 4 - 1940 May 16 (Box 79)
    - Smokeless Powder - Correspondence and Memoranda 1937 Dec. - 1940 July (Box 79)
    - Speeches, 2 folders 1937 July - 1938 March (Box 79)
    - Speeches, 5 folders 1938 April - 1940 Aug. (Box 80)
    - Speeches - Correspondence to Johnson and Replies re: Speeches, 3 folders 1937 Oct.-1940 July (Box 81)
    - Speech, Armistice Day, Welch, W. Va. - Newspaper Clippings 1939 Nov. (Box 81)
    - Speech, Army Day - Newspaper Clippings 1940 April (Box 81)
    - Speech, B'nai B'rith Celebration - Newspaper Clippings 1940 Feb. (Box 81)
    - Speech, Boston City Club - Newspaper Clippings 1940 Jan. (Box 81)
    - Speech, "Construction in Peace and War" - Newspaper Clippings 1940 Feb. (Box 81)
    - Speech, Engineering Society of Western Pennsylvania - Newspaper Clippings 1940 Feb. - March (Box 81)
    - Speech, Junior Chamber of Commerce - Newspaper Clippings 1940 April (Box 81)
    - Speech, Milwaukee - Newspaper Clippings 1940 March (Box 81)
    - Speech, New York Herald-Tribune Forum - Newspaper Clippings 1939 Sept.-Oct. (Box 81)
    - Speech, N. Y. State Bankers Association 1940 Jan.-Feb. (Box 81)
    - Speech, Southern Society of New York - Newspaper Clippings 1939 Nov. (Box 82)
    - Speech, West Va. State Hotel Convention - Newspaper Clippings 1939 Nov. (Box 82)
    - State Department - Correspondence between Johnson and State Dept. 1938 March-1939 Oct. (Box 82)
    - State Judicial Convention, W. Va.- Correspondence re: Johnson's Address 1940 July (Box 82)
    - Statistics Branch - Letter to Col. Ayres from Johnson 1940 March 13 (Box 82)
    - Statistics on number of Construction Workers, Industrial Production 1940 June-July (Box 82)
    - Strategic Materials - Correspondence and Documents 1938 Dec.-1940 May (Box 82)
    - Supply Arms and Services - Minutes of Weekly Conference with Johnson, 2 folders 1939 Sept.-1940 July (Box 82)
    - U. S. Employment Service - Correspondence and Papers 1937 July-1938 Oct. (Box 82)
    - U. S. Employment Service - Correspondence 1937 July-1939 Aug. (Box 82)
    - University of Va.-Correspondence and Papers re: Alumni 1937 June-1940 Jan. (Box 82)
    - University Club - Correspondence and Printed Material 1937 June-1939 May (Box 83)
    - Upper Monogahela Valley Association, West Va. - Correspondence and Papers 1937 Aug.-1938 Oct. (Box 83)
    - Veterans Advisory Commission, Alabama - Correspondence 1937 Sept. - 1938 May (Box 83)
    - Veterans' Hospitalization - Correspondence ca. 1937-ca. 1940 (Box 83)
    - Veterans Placement Service (Social Security Board) - Papers 1939-1940 (Box 83)
    - Vice-Presidency of Johnson - Correspondence re: Vice Presidency of Johnson in Oregon Primary 1940 March - July (Box 83)
    - War Department - Correspondence re: Records 1937 July - 1940 April (Box 83)
    - War Resources Board - Correspondence and Papers re: Creation of Board 1937 Oct.-1939 March (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Correspondence and Press Releases re: Formation of Board 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Correspondence between Johnson and Members 1939 Aug.-Dec. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Correspondence re: Dates of Meetings 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Correspondence and Memoranda re: Funds 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - General Correspondence 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Offers of Service 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Correspondence re: Press Releases 1939 Aug.-Dec. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Comments from Elder Statesmen: Ayres, Baruch, Crowell, Replogle 1939 Aug.-Sept. (Box 84)
    - War Resources Board - Newspaper Clippings 1939 Sept.-Dec. (Box 84)
    - "We the People" Radio Broadcast - Correspondence re: Johnson's Address 1940 July (Box 84)
    - West Virginia Chamber of Commerce - Correspondence 1937 Aug.-1940 July (Box 84)
    - White House - Correspondence with President Roosevelt and Staff 1937 June-1940 May (Box 84)
    - White House Press Conferences - Memoranda of Minutes of Conference for Secretary of War 1939 Sept - 1940 July (Box 84)
    - Work Progress Administration - Correspondence 1939 Oct.-Nov. (Box 84)
    - World's Fair, 1939, San Francisco - Correspondence and Printed Material 1938 Jan.-Nov. (Box 84)
  - Subseries C, Confidential Case File
    - Confidential Case File - A -W, 19 folders 1937-1939 (Box 85)
  - Subseries D, Appointments Schedule, 1987-1940
    - Daily Journal, 3 volumes 1938-1940 July 25 (Box 86)
    - Daily Schedule of Louis Johnson and a carbon 1937 June 21-Dec. 31 (Box 87)
    - Daily Schedule of Louis Johnson 1938 Jan. 1-May 15 (Box 87)
    - Daily Schedule of Louis Johnson (carbon) 1938 Jan. 1-Feb. 10 (Box 87)
    - Appointments Calendar 1940 Jan. 2-Dec. 28 (Box 87)
    - Correspondence Index (incomplete) of Harry H. Woodring as Sec. Of War, 1937 Jan. 1-Feb. 19, and of Louis Johnson as Acting Sec. Of War, 1937 June 28-Dec. 31 1937 (Box 87)
    - Correspondence Index (incomplete) of Louis Johnson 1938 (Box 87)
    - Correspondence Index (incomplete) of Louis Johnson 1939 (Box 87)
    - Index of Louis Johnson photographs 1937-1940 (Box 87)
  - Subseries E, Speeches, 1937-1940
    - Speeches by Louis Johnson, Assistant Secretary of War, 4 folders 1937 July 15 - 1939 April 15 (Box 88)
    - Speeches by Louis Johnson, Assistant Secretary of War, 3 folders 1939 May 1-1940 Aug. 6 (Box 89)
    - Address before American Legion, Wheeling, W. Va. 1940 Sept. 2 (Box 89)
  - Subseries F, Miscellaneous
    - Letter of resignation from Louis Johnson as Assistant Secretary of War 1940 July 25 (Box 90)
    - Private Correspondence and Papers taken from Johnson's desk as Assistant Secretary of War, in 1940. Includes memoranda from FDR and the White House 1937 July 28-1940 July 4 (Box 90)
    - Annual Report of the Assistant Secretary of War 1938-TMs (copy) (Box 90)
    - Address List - Government Officials 1938 Nov. 25 (Box 90)
    - List of allotments of contracts for Air Corps, Engineers, Signal Corps, Quartermaster Corps, etc. 1939 July 12 (Box 90)
    - Application for articles of Incorporation of the Democratic War Veterans of Pennsylvania 1938 June (Box 90)
    - Booklet, The National Aviation Forum, digest of proceedings, includes a speech by Louis Johnson, Asst. Sec. of War 1939 Jan.-Feb. (Box 90)
    - Booklet, "The New Army of the United States," the War Department 1941 Aug. 1 (Box 90)
    - Booklet, "Proceedings of National Airport Conference," U.S. Department of Commerce, Bureau of Air Commerce 1937 Dec. 6-7 (Box 90)
    - Booklet, W. P. A. Picatinny Arsenal 1935 Sept. 19-1937 Dec. 31 (Box 90)
    - Brief in behalf of National Bituminous Coal Commission, proposed Trade Agreement between U. S. and Venezuela 1938 Aug. 6 (Box 91)
    - Brief, "Outlining Advantages and Qualifications of Wheeling - Ohio County Airport, and Wheeling, West Virginia for Aeronautical Research, Laboratory," by the Wheeling Chamber of Commerce 1939 Aug. 30 (Box 91)
    - Case file - Investigation, U. S. Military Academy 1938 April-May (Box 91)
    - Transcript of the Cornerstone Ceremony of the FDR Library, Inc. at Hyde Park, N. Y. 1939 Nov. 19 (Box 91)
    - Dedication ceremonies commemorating the services of the Railroad War Board of 1917 1940 April 26 (Box 91)
    - Certificate, The Association of Military Surgeons, Honorary Membership 1939 May 8 (Box 91)
    - List, Post-War Planning Commission, the American Legion, Louis Johnson, Chairman n.d. (Box 91)
    - Reserve Commission, Lieutenant Colonel of Infantry, of Louis Johnson 1937 Aug. 19 (Box 91)
    - Recommendation for the Committee on Civil Aviation Legislation by the National Aeronautic Assoc. ca. 1937 (Box 91)
    - Digest, "Houston, 1938," by the Chamber of Commerce 1938 (Box 91)
    - Directory, Procurement Planning District Offices 1938 Oct. (Box 91)
    - List of exhibits contained in Museum, Springfield Armory, Springfield, Mass. 1938 March 18 (Box 91)
    - Flight Record of Louis Johnson as the Assistant Secretary of War from 1937 June 27 to 1940 Aug. 7 1940 Aug. (Box 91)
    - Itineraries, schedules, and miscellaneous papers of Louis Johnson 1937-1938 Aug. (Box 91)
    - Itineraries, schedules, and miscellaneous papers of Louis Johnson, 2 folders 1938 Sept.-1940 June (Box 92)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders ca. 1937-ca. 1940 (Box 92)
    - Papers re: Municipal Airport problems 1937 Oct.-Nov. (Box 92)
    - Miscellaneous Newsletters 1939 (Box 93)
    - Organization Charts of the Peace Organization Planning Branch, O. A. S. W.; the Army-Navy Munitions Board; and the War Resources Administration 1938-1939 (Box 93)
    - Souvenir pamphlet, "The Panama Canal, Twenty-fifth Anniversary" 1939 Aug. 15 (Box 93)
    - Pamphlet, "This is Toledo" 1937 (Box 93)
    - Miscellaneous Programs, 2 folders 1936-1940 (Box 93)
    - Report, "First Month of Britain's War Economy" and Dwight F. Davis's Report to Brookings Institution on "Great Britain's Industrial and Financial Mobilization" 1939 Oct. 10 (Box 94)
    - Miscellaneous Reports 1937-1939 (Box 94)
    - Resolutions, Adopted by the Executive Council, American Federation of Labor 1940 Feb. 2 (Box 94)
    - Statement, "Democracy's Duty and Our National Defense," by Dr. William W. Christmas 1939 Oct. (Box 94)
    - Statement re: Fishing vessels off Alaskan coast 1937 July (Box 94)
    - Testimony of Col. Edgar S. Gorrell, President, Air Transport Association of America, before Inter-Departmental Committee on Civil Aviation Legislation and Regulations 1937 Oct. 25 (Box 94)
    - Transcripts of papers re: the seal of the Department of War 1800-1894 (Box 94)
    - Louis Johnson's copy of War Contract Forms recommended by War Contract Board 1938 Dec. 19 (Box 94)
- Series III, papers of Louis Arthur Johnson, 1940-1948
  - Subseries A, Correspondence
    - Correspondence with Cordell Hull, Secretary of State 1943 July 9 - 1944 Sept. 21 (Box 95)
    - Correspondence with Franklin D. Roosevelt and Stephen Early, Secretary to the President, including a letter from Truman 1940-1945 (Box 95)
    - Correspondence - General 1940 July 24-1947 Sept. 12 (Box 95)
  - Subseries B Reports, Proceedings and Minutes, 1944-1946
    - Proceedings, Postwar Planning Commission, the American Legion 1944 Feb. 4, May 1 (Box 95)
    - Minutes, West Virginia Department of Veterans Affairs, Council Meeting, Jackson Mills, West Va. 1946 May 26 (Box 95)
    - Report of Military affairs section, National Defense Committee, the American Legion ca. 1946 (Box 95)
  - Subseries C, Speeches and Addresses
    - TMs (copy), Address of Louis Johnson to the 1941 Dept. Convention, the American Legion of Texas 1941 Aug. 17 (Box 95)
    - Address, Thirty-Second Annual Convention, the International Claim Association, "America at the Cross Roads" 1941 Sept. 8 (Box 95)
    - Address by Col. Louis Johnson, Armistice Day, the American Legion 1941 Nov. 11 (Box 95)
    - Address of Louis Johnson before the National Convention of the American Legion 1942 Sept. 19 (Box 95)
    - Address by Louis Johnson, before the State Bar Association and the General Assembly of the State of South Carolina, "The Next Generation and World War Three" 1943 March 3 (Box 95)
    - Address by Louis Johnson, before the American Legion, Department of West Virginia 1943 Sept. 6 (Box 96)
    - Address, National Convention of the American Legion 1943 Sept. 21 (Box 96)
    - Speech re: American Legion by Sam Reynolds, District Legion Convention 1943 Oct. 26 (Box 96)
    - Address, "America Must Have American Legion Leadership" by Louis Johnson and other American Legion addresses 1943, n. d. (Box 96)
    - Speeches of Louis Johnson before various groups 1943-1947, n.d. (Box 96)
    - TMs (carbon), Address of Louis Johnson, Dedication of Legion Home of Huntington, West Virginia 1945 May 27 (Box 96)
    - Statement by Louis Johnson before National Postwar Conference, St. Moritz Hotel, N. Y. C., "The Consumer and Employment" 1945 June 28 (Box 96)
    - Speech, 27th Annual Convention, Department of West Virginia, the American Legion 1945 Oct. 6 (Box 96)
    - Excerpts from speech of Louis Johnson, Thomas Jefferson Club of Wood County, Parkersburg, West Virginia 1946 April 13 (Box 96)
    - Talk for Louis Johnson, NBC Network, Memorial Day, "We Shall Speak for Them" 1946 May 30 (Box 96)
    - Excerpts from the speech of Louis Johnson, The West Virginia Association of Insurance Agents Annual Convention 1946 July 19 (Box 96)
    - Address of Robert P. Patterson, Secretary of War, before the American Legion National Convention 1946 Oct. 2 (Box 96)
    - Address of Owen Brewster, Senator, before the 28th Annual National Convention of the American Legion 1946 Oct. 2 (Box 96)
    - Address, American Legion Twenty-ninth Annual National Convention 1947 Aug. 28 (Box 96)
    - Excerpts from address, Annual Dinner Meeting, St. Louis Post, American Ordnance Association 1948 April 19 (Box 96)
    - Excerpts from address of Louis Johnson, Annual National Congress, Daughters of American Revolution 1948 April 21 (Box 96)
    - Speech, "The World Situation as I See It," 57th Continental Congress, Daughters of American Revolution ca. 1948 May (Box 96)
  - Subseries D, Miscellaneous
    - Citation to accompany the award of the Medal of Merit to Louis Johnson 1947 July 16 (Box 96)
    - Miscellaneous 1944 (Box 96)
    - Three issues of National Whirligig1940 July 29-Aug. 6 (Box 96)
    - Papers re: Post-War Planning 1944 June 7, n. d. (Box 96)
    - Presentation of American Legion's Distinguished Service Medal to the late Franklin Delano Roosevelt, by Louis Johnson 1945 Nov. 18 (Box 96)
    - Eleven Point Program for preserving the American way of life after the War, by the American Legion, Louis Johnson, Chairman 1941-1947 (Box 96)
    - American Legion Resolution re: Universal Military Training ca. 1945 (Box 96)
- Series IV, Papers re India
  - Subseries A, Correspondence with Jawaharlal Nehru
    - Correspondence with Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru or about Nehru 1942 April-June (Box 97)
    - TL (carbon), Louis Johnson to Jawaharlal Nehru 1945 Oct. 18 (Box 97)
    - Correspondence with Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru 1946 Aug.-Nov. (Box 97)
    - TL, Louis Johnson to Jawaharlal Nehru 1947 Aug. 15 (Box 97)
    - TLS, Jawaharlal Nehru to Louis Johnson 1947 Feb. 26 (Box 97)
    - Correspondence with Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru 1949 Nov. 6-Dec. 5 (Box 97)
    - Correspondencewith Prime Minister Jawaharlal Nehru and Indira Gandhi 1950 Oct. 24-1964 June 12 (Box 97)
  - Subseries B, Correspondence re India
    - Correspondence re: India, 9 folders 1942 March-1944 (Box 97)
    - Correspondence re: India, 4 folders 1945-1948 (Box 98)
    - Correspondence re: India 1950-1958
  - Subseries C, Correspondence re Nehru's Dinner
    - Correspondence re: Nehru's Dinner, Greenbrier Hotel 1949 June-Oct. (Box 98)
    - Correspondence re: Nehru's dinner, Greenbrier Hotel 1949 Nov.-1950 Jan. (Box 99)
    - Correspondence and papers re: the Dinner of the Sec. Of Defense and Mrs. Johnson in honor of Pandit Nehru at White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, Oct. 29, 1949 1949 (Box 99)
    - Correspondence re: Nehru's Dinner Greenbrier Hotel - Acceptances 1949 (Box 99)
    - Correspondence re: Nehru's Dinner Greenbrier Hotel - Regrets 1949 (Box 99)
    - Papers re: Nehru's Dinner Greenbrier Hotel - Lists of names 1949-1950 (Box 100)
  - Subseries D, Miscellaneous
    - Script of a Radio Broadcast by Colonel Johnson to the people of India 1942 April 23 (Box 100)
    - Printed Address: Sir Stafford Cripps to the House of Commons 1942 April 28 (Box 100)
    - Report No. 3, Government of India Mission, mainly re: Defense of India 1942 [April] (Box 100)
    - Two Outlines re: Indian nationalism 1942 May 11, n. d. (Box 100)
    - International Conciliation, "The Cripps Mission to India," no. 381 1942 June (Box 100)
    - Report of the American Technical Mission to India, "A Survey of India's Industrial Production for War Purposes" 1942 Aug. (Box 100)
    - TMs (copy), "A Four-fold Plan for India," by unidentified author 1942 Sept. 11 (Box 100)
    - Articles from the Nation, re: the Cripps mission in India 1942 Sept. 19-Dec. 5 (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous papers re: India 1942, n. d. (Box 100)
    - 15 Issues of India Today, Monthly Bulletin of the India League of America 1942-1948 (Box 100)
    - Paper, "American Mission to India headed by Louis Johnson" 1942 (Box 100)
    - Miscellaneous Newsclippings and Bulletins re: India ca. 1942-ca. 1955, n. d. (Box 100)
    - TMs(copy), Report, "Famine in India," by Sirdar J. J. Singh 1943 Oct. 27 (Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material re: India ca. 1943-ca. 1947 (Box 101)
    - A Plan of Economic Development for India by Purshotamdas Thakurdas 1944 Jan. (Box 101)
    - Constitutional Proposals of the Sapru Committee 1945 Dec. (Box 101)
    - 3 Issues of Voice of India1946 Nov.-1947 March (Box 101)
    - TMs(copy) Speech of William Phillips at India League Dinner 1947 April 15 (Box 101)
    - Report, "Memorial Meeting" of the India League of America, to pay tribute to the memory of Mahatma Gandhi 1948 Feb. 7 (Box 101)
    - Newsletter, Pakistan Affairs, vol. 11, no. 7 1948 Sept. 22 (Box 101)
    - Bulletin, Government of India Information Services 1949 Sept. 22 (Box 101)
    - TMs (copy), "The Triumph of Nehru," by J. J. Singh [ca. 1949?] (Box 101)
    - 5 Issues of Indiagram issued by the Embassy of India 1954 July 13-1956 Jan. 6 (Box 101)
    - Bulletins from Information Service of India, Embassy of India 1956 Dec. (Box 101)
    - TMs (copy), Lecture, "Riddle of India," by Louis Fischer _ Feb. 23 (Box 101)
    - Miscellaneous secretarial notes _July-Aug., n. d. (Box 101)
  - Subseries E, Photographs
    - Photographs of Louis Johnson as Chairman of the United States mission to India [1942] (Box 101)
    - Photograph of Jawaharlal Nehru, Louis Fischer and [Mrs. Gandhi?] n.d. (Box 101)
    - Map of India and Ceylon n.d. (Box 101)
- Series V. Papers of the Secretary of Defense
  - Subseries A, General Correspondence
    - Correspondence with Captain L. A. Abercrombie 1949-1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with Dean Acheson, Secretary of State 1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with Frank J. Agnew 1949 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with A. V. Alexander, C. H.: M. P., Minister of Defense, London 1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with C. E. Alfaro of the Eloy Alfaro Foundation 1949 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with George E. Allen 1949 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with General Leven C. Allen 1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with Raymond B. Allen 1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with Mrs. Henry H. Arnold 1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence re: Autographing a placard containing a quotation by Abraham Lincoln 1949-1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with Colonel Jesse Auton 1949-1950 (Box 102)
    - Correspondence with Louis Fabian Bachrach 1949-1950 (Box 102)